JILL SANTOS

Elementary Education Professional

Personal Info

Phone

(555) 555-5555

E-mail

jillsantos1@gmail.com

www

www.janesantos.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/janesantos1

Twitter

twitter.com/janesantos1

Skills

Curriculum Design

Advanced

Time Management

Excellent

Differentiated Instruction

Intermediate

Student Safety

Advanced

Engaging **Elementary Education Teacher** with over five years of experience guiding individualized instruction and meeting state standards. Proficient in English as a Second Language (ESL) instruction and Individualized Education Plans (IEPs). Seeking to bring intelligent, enthusiastic solutions to your students at Smith High School.

Experience

2013-08 - Fourth Grade Teacher

present

West School District, Smith Elementary

- Increased standardized test score for students in science (30%) and reading (24%) by implementing creative coursework into the curriculum.
- Established an extracurricular book club that resulted in 50+ students joining and reading an average of 9 books a year.
- Integrated technology into learning with Smart Boards, iPads, and computers.
- Built a collaborative and friendly classroom environment using and enforcing behavior guides, team teaching, and interactive learning.

2012-08 - Teaching Assistant

2013-08 West School District, Jones Elementary

- Worked in both a kindergarten and first grade classroom.
- Collaborated with classroom teacher to administer tests and curriculum instruction to students.
- · Maintained constant communication

2011-08 - Interactive Field Experience

2011-12

South School District, Wilson Elementary

- · Provided teacher and classroom support.
- · Led educational games and group activities.
- Leveraged knowledge in special education to support teachers and students within self-contained (resource) and inclusion classrooms.

Education

2008-08 - University of Texas at Austin Bachelor of Science in

2012-05

Elementary Education

- Graduated Cum Laude; asked be commencement speaker at graduation.
- Active member of Alpha Phi.

Volunteer

2014-01 - Big Brothers, Big Sisters

present

Active Volunteer

· Connected and built a relationship with talented 9-year old girl.

Certificates

2015 Certified in First Aid & CPR (American Red Cross)

2014 TX Teacher Certified